[
    {
        "question": "The city of Berkeley is located across a bay from what other city?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is nicknamed the `Motor City`?",
        "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
        "question": "What four US states begin with the letter `W`?",
        "answer": "Washington, West Virginia, Wisconsin and Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Laguna Madre is located between mainland Texas and what island?",
        "answer": "Padre Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river defines the border between Texas and Mexico?",
        "answer": "Rio Grande River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Big Bend National Park protects what mountain range?",
        "answer": "Chisos Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Tahoe is located in which US states?",
        "answer": "California and Nevada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state is nicknamed the `Grand Canyon State`?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to Okefenokee National Wildlife Refuge?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest town in Texas?",
        "answer": "Nacogdoches -- It is over 300 years old and was believed to have been founded by the Caddo Indians."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the biggest desert in Australia?",
        "answer": "Great Victoria Desert -- Located in Western and South Australia, it is home to several nature reserves and a national park."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia`s Great Barrier Reef?",
        "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which US state would you find the world`s only ventriloquism museum?",
        "answer": "Kentucky -- The Vent Haven Museum in Fort Mitchell, Kentucky is the private collection of businessman William Shakespeare Berger."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. city can you stroll down 6 1/2 Avenue?",
        "answer": "New York City -- Made official in 2012, the street is situated between 6th Avenue and 7th Avenue."
    },
    {
        "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?",
        "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Pine Barrens in southern New Jersey is the supposed home of which legendary creature?",
        "answer": "Jersey Devil"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?",
        "answer": "Akihabara"
    },
    {
        "question": "From 1964 to 1980, what country was known as Rhodesia?",
        "answer": "Zimbabwe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Mayan Temple of Kukulcan located?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the first underwater art museum in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Santa Rosa Beach, Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state claims to be the diner capital of the world?",
        "answer": "New Jersey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "South Africa has water access to which oceans?",
        "answer": "Indian and Atlantic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country does South Africa completely surround?",
        "answer": "Lesotho"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lesotho is landlocked by which African country?",
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river does the city of Dublin stand?",
        "answer": "Liffey River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two countries border Uruguay?",
        "answer": "Brazil and Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many stars are there on the New Zealand flag?",
        "answer": "Four"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Andorra?",
        "answer": "Andorra la Vella"
    },
    {
        "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Andorra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Andorra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Andorra is part of which continent?",
        "answer": "Europe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What strait separates New Zealand`s North and South Islands?",
        "answer": "Cook Strait"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is home to the Negev Desert?",
        "answer": "Israel"
    },
    {
        "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country",
        "answer": "Norway"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CN Tower is in which Canadian city?",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science Located?",
        "answer": "Virginia Key, Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the National Animal of Mauritius?",
        "answer": "The Dodo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nickname of The Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta, the largest delta in the world?",
        "answer": "The Green Delta"
    },
    {
        "question": "What countries make up the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "England, Wales, Scotland, and Northern Ireland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country has the highest average rainfall in the world?",
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country would you find Mount Elbrus in?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states does India have?",
        "answer": "28"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many territories does India have?",
        "answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What three countries share the island of Borneo?",
        "answer": "Indonesia, Malaysia and Brunei"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Machu Picchu is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Peru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was formerly known as East Pakistan?",
        "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country do the Galapagos Islands belong to?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    }
]